John Ferro

5241 Morgan Ave S. Minneapolis, MN 55419 jonafi@gmail.com (516) 965-2434

github.com/jonafi
linkedin.com/in/JohnFerro

SUMMARY

Web developer with 15 years experience of front-end and back-end coding. Has held a variety of roles including digital marketing producer and digital consultant. Recently completed a 6 month Full Stack web certification course through University of Minnesota. Writes clear concise code, communicates well with technical and non-technical people.

SKILLS

Full Stack Web developer

Core Technologies: HTML, CSS, javaScript, MySQL, PHP
New Technologies: Node, React, MongoDB, Express, BootStrap
Additional software libraries and platforms: jQuery, Git, Photoshop

Digital Producer

Email: Campaign content creation, design, coding, email list management, distribution, and post-email KPI analysis *Product launch support*: Microsites, press releases, surveys, trade shows

EXPERIENCE

2017-2021 | J&D Tech | Minneapolis, MN Web Developer

Completed short term front-end & back-end assignments as a freelancer. Acted as content manager, archivist, and digital consultant for a number of clients.

Project Highlight: PeterOstroushko.com

- Recovered expired domain and set up a new site on a new hosting platform.
- Designed and built bootstrap based site for frequently changing updated content.
- Trained users to use third party marketing platform for email promotions.

2011-2016 | MechoShade | Long Island City, NY

Web Lead

Under the supervision of the Marketing Director, led a team of writers and designers to create digital deliverables such as websites and mass email communications.

Key Projects:

- Website overhaul: Led a design refresh and code rewrite that halved page load times and reduced bounce rate by 50%. Launched an inexpensive Google adwords campaign and adopted SEO best practices that doubled website traffic and improved the quality of lead generation.
- ERP launch: Edited and branded software elements for Infor SyteLine launch.
 Coded extensive edits to customer portal interface, training modules, and print invoices and created a branded experience for an off-the-shelf product.
- Trade show booth update: Added QR codes to booth art that linked to product demo videos. Created a "serverless" website for the sales team to use in convention centers with poor WiFi coverage.

2000-2008 | Ernst & Young | New York, NY

Web developer

Paired with a senior developer to build and maintain the branding intranet site for EY.com. Using the Lotus Domino platform created a photo library and document repository used by 130,000 employees.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota Coding Bootcamp - Full Stack Web Development September 2020